Ollie Wright

Game Designer/Programmer

Portfolio: https://ollieguy.github.io/portfolio/

GitHub: https://github.com/OllieGuy

PROFILE

As a game designer with 6 years of experience with game creation, and 15 years of gaming (specifically open world and first person shooter games), I have a keen interest in game development, spending much of my free time carrying out research on game design principles, through reviewing essays and articles, as well as watching videos made by creators such as Game Maker's Toolkit and Writing on Games. I am also a very sociable person, and was a part of my university's esports society, and thrive in team based environments.

EXPERIENCE

Curation, University Project — Design and AI Programming September 2023 - May 2024

Curation is a museum management simulation game created alongside Frontier Developments. I focused on creating NPCs that displayed personality and encouraging emergent gameplay through their behaviour, and the underlying system/tech design Skills: Unity, C#, Modular AI behaviour, Technical Design, System Design

Press Space, University Project — Solo (design, code, art) February 2023 - May 2023

Press Space is a satirical branching narrative game, featuring nine different endings. The game was designed to critique the relationship between players and developer, as well as the concept of free will within games

Cedrik's Crown, University Project — Lead Designer & QA October 2022 - January 2023

Skills: Design for game feel, C#, Narrative experience, Full stack development

Cedrik's Crown is a 2-4 player dungeon crawler RPG board game. The enemy encounters were balanced by a program written by myself in C#. I focused mostly on the core gameplay loop and the player experience, in addition to playtesting extensively in order to ensure balance and player engagement being retained Skills: Understanding of design principles and balancing, team leadership, C#, C++

EDUCATION

University of Portsmouth, Portsmouth — First Class degree in Computer Games Technology (BSc) - September 2021 - July 2024

Graduated with a 4.16 GPA, with all year module mark averages being First Class

The Henley College, Henley — A-Levels – May 2021

Maths (A) Economics (A) Computer Science (A)

ollieswright02@gmail.com

PROGRAM PROFICIENCY

Visual Studio 2022/VSCode Unity & PlasticSCM C# C++ Git/GitHub Microsoft Office suite Adobe Photoshop Adobe Premiere Pro

Confluence

Iira

SKILLS

Working with teams

Meeting and engaging with new people

Effective communication with co-workers and clients

Very strong work ethic and willingness to learn

Positive attitude/outlook and enthusiastic approach

OUALIFICATIONS

Archery Level 1 Coaching Award Work Experience at the SAE Institute of Technology and Media 2018

INTERESTS

Game Development Game Design **Games Programming** Artificial intelligence/machine learning Media Theory and films Gaming